<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Books on Cerebral Mastication: Something to Chew On</title>
    <link>https://cerebralmastication.netlify.com/tags/books/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Books on Cerebral Mastication: Something to Chew On</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 May 2014 12:56:15 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://cerebralmastication.netlify.com/tags/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Teens and the Internet...</title>
      <link>https://cerebralmastication.netlify.com/2014/05/teens-and-the-internet/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2014 12:56:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cerebralmastication.netlify.com/2014/05/teens-and-the-internet/</guid>
      <description>Given that I have a small version of myself running around my house, I think about how she&amp;rsquo;ll use the Internet when she gets older. Just the other day she, &amp;ldquo;Asked Google something&amp;rdquo; which made me realize that, although she&amp;rsquo;s just barely literate, my kid is going to &amp;ldquo;be online&amp;rdquo; for the rest of her life. Although I&amp;rsquo;m not really sure what &amp;ldquo;be online&amp;rdquo; will mean for her over the years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tolstoy Dichotomy, Part Two</title>
      <link>https://cerebralmastication.netlify.com/2009/06/tolstoy-dichotomy-part-two/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2009 17:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cerebralmastication.netlify.com/2009/06/tolstoy-dichotomy-part-two/</guid>
      <description>[caption id=&amp;ldquo;&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;alignleft&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;120&amp;rdquo; caption=&amp;ldquo;Tatiana Samoilova as Anna-bobanna&amp;rdquo;][/caption]
So back in March, 2009 I blogged about a phenomenon I called the Anna Karenina Yield Anomaly. In short, I postulated that in the production of crops the idea of a national &amp;lsquo;good year&amp;rsquo; pretty much means everyone had a good yield and a national &amp;lsquo;bad year&amp;rsquo; meant that some had an OK year and some were having a terrible year. And thus I made myself seem more literate than I am by linking that phenomenon back to Tolstoy and his line “All happy families are happy in the same way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#39;Sully&#39; Sullenberger voice recordings</title>
      <link>https://cerebralmastication.netlify.com/2009/02/sully-sullenberger-voice-recordings/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2009 14:19:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cerebralmastication.netlify.com/2009/02/sully-sullenberger-voice-recordings/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;ve all heard all the stories about how &amp;lsquo;Sully&amp;rsquo; Sullenberger has to go through a special line at the airport because his large brass balls always set off the metal detectors. Well. It&amp;rsquo;s true, and here&amp;rsquo;s proof:
Ever since Sept 15th, 2008 I have had a bit of a fetish with studying accident theory (that&amp;rsquo;s when our financial system started its current free fall). One of the best books I have read on how big studs like Sully make decisions is the book Sources of Power by Gary Klein.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>